Countries worldwide are battling a discrete yet fierce information war.
這是個全世界在檯面下 情報戰打得如火如荼的時代
Two countries are in a standoff.
其中有兩個國家僵持不下
Ostania in the east. Westalis in the west.
東方的東國跟西方的西國
Westalis launched Operation Strix to find out the movements
東國政府計畫掀起戰爭 為了查清該國重要人物的動向
of key figures in the Ostanian government, who are plotting a war.
西國開始了代號“梟”的行動
Highly skilled Agent Twilight, was put in charge of the operation.
這項任務由技藝超群的特務黃昏負責
The man with a hundred different faces, was given a mission
這名面孔千變萬化的男人 收到了一項任務
to create a family.
就是建立家庭
Father, Loid Forger, a psychiatrist.
父親,洛伊德佛傑,是一名心理醫師
His true identity is a spy. Codename is Twilight.
他的真實身分是間諜,代號“黃昏”
Mother, Yor Forger, a city hall employee.
母親,約兒佛傑,是市政廳公務員
Her true identity is an assassin. Codename is Thorn Princess.
她的真實身分是職業殺手 代號“睡美人”
Daughter, Anya Forger.
女兒,安妮亞佛傑
Her true identity is a telepath who can read minds.
真實身分是具有讀心術的超能力者
Dog, Bond Forger.
寵物犬,彭德佛傑
A psychic canine that can glimpse the future.
是一隻能夠預知未來的超能力狗狗
For their own personal interests, they created a fake family.
他們為了各自的利益 組成了虛假的家庭
The mission continues, as three of them hide their identities from each other.
在彼此互相隱瞞真實身分的情況下 持續進行任務
ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
(遠藤達哉原創作品 連載於集英社《SHONEN JUMP PLUS》)
MISSION:37 PART OF THE FAMILY
劇名:任務:37 家族的一員
Bond, let's go for a walk.
彭德,去散步吧
You wanna come along?
妳要一起來嗎?
Anya's not going.
安妮亞不去
Anya's really busy right now.
安妮亞現在很忙
- This is the highest level of difficulty. - Origami?
- 這是最高難度 - 摺紙?
She says it's popular at school right now.
說是現在學校很流行這個
She's concentrating so hard.
她難得專注力這麼好
Since Anya's not coming, maybe I'll train Bond instead of taking him on a walk.
既然安妮亞不來 與其帶彭德去散步,不如訓練牠一下
We'll be off.
那我們出發了
Bye, Loid. Bye, Bond.
路上小心,洛伊德先生、彭德先生
Go!
去吧
Good boy.
很好
Incapacitate the target by going for the arms and legs.
攻擊對方的手腳 讓對方喪失行動能力
Don't bite vitals areas that would cause critical injuries.
不可以攻擊會造成致命傷的要害喔
They need to be alive to give us intel.
要留活口才能問出情報
You jerk! Did you forget that I took good care of you?
混蛋,你是忘了我照顧過你嗎?
Bad boy! Once you grip them with your teeth, don't let go!
不可以,一旦咬住了就絕不要鬆口!
Letting go will not only put you in danger, but biting the suspect
鬆口會讓你陷入危險,對歹徒
multiple times can lead to critical injuries.
咬太多次的話,也可能造成致命傷
You're too gentle. Barking and biting might not be your forte.
你的性情太溫和 吠叫跟撕咬應該不是你的強項
By the way,
話說回來
why am I playing the role of the suspect?
我為什麼要扮演歹徒的角色?
- Listen up. I'm an informant. - It can't be helped. I'm training Bond.
- 聽清楚了,我是情報商 - 要訓練彭德,沒辦法嘛
"It can't be helped," my ass!
什麼叫“沒辦法”!
Explain yourself in 500 words!
你用五百字給我解釋一下!
The situation around us is threatening and dangerous.
我們周遭的情勢充滿威脅又危險
- So we must be prepared just in case. - That explanation wasn't good enough.
- 為了以防萬一,要做好準備 - 這種說法說服不了我
All right. That's enough for the suppression and securing training.
好,壓制跟看守的訓練應該夠了
Let's move onto screening scents and explosives detection.
接下來就進行辨別氣味 以及尋找炸彈的訓練吧
This training will be tough.
這項訓練可不容易喔
I have to be part of that too?
那個我也要演嗎?
I have to play the part of the bomber?
我得扮演炸彈客嗎?
What's wrong? Are you having a hard time concentrating?
怎麼了?難道是失去專注力了?
Project Apple
“APPLE”計劃
was a study to create intelligent military dogs, right?
是為了製造聰明的軍用犬 所進行的研究吧?
He was forced to train back then, so he must be sick and tired of it.
牠被你逼著做那麼多訓練 一定是覺得受夠了,很累了吧
I see.
這樣啊
You can't even do something this simple, you useless mongrel.
這麼簡單的事情都不會嗎? 真是沒用的狗
This project is a failure.
這項計劃失敗了
It's time to get rid of these dogs.
是時候該把這些狗處理掉了
To dogs, both training and taking part in real battles,
對狗來說,訓練跟實戰兩者
is not much different than playing.
都跟玩遊戲沒有區別
Make the training more enjoyable for him.
至少讓牠可以更享受訓練的過程吧
That's something you really need to work on.
你在這方面實在有待加強
Take him on a walk for a change of pace.
帶牠去散個步,轉換心情吧
- Anyways, I'll be off. - Wait!
- 那我就閃人了 - 等等!
Let's go for a walk.
去散步吧
Wow! You made so many of them.
妳做了好多個喔
Those stars are so cute.
好可愛的星星喔
These aren't just normal stars.
這可不是一般的星星喔
Anya Forger, you have been awarded with a Stella Star!
安妮亞佛傑,頒給妳一枚星星!
Don't scavenge for food.
不可以亂吃喔
My ice cream!
我的冰淇淋!
I only got to eat a little bit of it!
我才吃了一點點而已!
What a loser!
好遜喔!
Starting today, your nickname is Ice Cream Dropper.
以後你的綽號就叫“手滑冰”
No way!
才不要!
Two scoops!
兩球冰淇淋!
It's so unfair that you get so much allowance.
不公平,你零用錢怎麼那麼多?
You protected that kid's food? Good boy.
你保護了小朋友的食物啊?真了不起
Bringing you into the family was worth it.
不枉讓你成為家裡的一員
Whoa!
等等!
What's up with this bear?
這隻熊是怎樣?
Is he after my ice cream?
難道牠想吃我的冰淇淋?
Stop it, Bond! What's wrong?
別鬧了,彭德!怎麼回事?
My ice cream!
我的冰淇淋!
I only got to eat a little bit of it!
我才吃了一點點而已!
Sorry, little guy. I'll get you another one!
抱歉,少年,我再買來賠你!
Three scoops!
三球冰淇淋!
- Must be nice. - I'm so jealous.
- 真好 - 好羨慕喔
It's so unlike you to go after someone else's food.
居然去搶別人的食物,真不像你
What got into you all of a sudden? Are you hungry?
你怎麼突然這樣?難道是餓了?
I'm so sorry! Are you all right? Call the ambulance!
真是對不起!還好嗎?叫救護車!
You're being weird today!
你今天很不對勁耶!
Whoa! What's up with this beast?
媽呀!這隻野獸要做什麼?
I'm so sorry!
對不起!
I apologize on my dog's behalf!
我替我家狗狗道歉!
That dog needs to be trained!
這隻狗真是欠人管教!
Biting an innocent stranger is absolutely preposterous!
居然去咬無辜的陌生人 實在太不像話了!
Seems like you need some training.
看來要對你多加訓練才行
Wow, Bond! You saved the future!
好棒喔,彭德!你拯救了未來!
How strange.
奇怪了
He completed both the socialization and obedience training.
明明已經完成 社會化訓練跟服從訓練了
And he's not an irrational dog to begin with, either.
而且牠本來並不是這樣失控的狗啊
Just as it is with Anya, I still have a lot to learn about Bond.
就跟我對安妮亞不夠了解一樣 我還得多認識一下彭德
Oh no! A bird pooped on me!
討厭!有鳥大便掉在我身上!
FORESEEING
(預知)
That's enough! We're getting rid of a dog like you!
給我適可而止 像你這種狗我們不要了!
Is he sick or something?
難道是哪裡不舒服嗎?
Should I take him to the vet?
要帶去看獸醫嗎?
- Daisy! - Ma'am, it's dangerous! Stand back!
- 黛西! - 不可以,太太,請後退!
Daisy is still inside!
黛西還在裡面!
No! My Daisy!
不要啊,黛西!
What's the matter?
怎麼了?
He's so restless today.
今天牠真的很焦躁不安呢
No! Stop!
不行,不可以!
That's...
那個是...
Someone call the fire department!
誰快去通知消防隊!
The fire is spreading faster than expected!
火勢蔓延的速度比預期的還快!
A fire? Did he react to this smell?
火災?是對這個味道產生的反應嗎?
- Is there anyone inside? - No worries. Everyone evacuated.
- 還有人在裡面嗎? - 不用擔心,人都已經撤離了
There's been lots of fire these days.
最近發生很多起火災呢
There's rumor that it's arson.
有謠言說是人為縱火呢
Where are the fire fighters?
消防車還沒到嗎?
Daisy! My Daisy!
黛西!
Idiot! Stay away! No one's inside!
笨蛋,別進去!裡面沒人了!
You should stay away too!
你不要跟著進去啊!
Wait, he might have caught someone's scent inside.
等等,也許牠是聞到了誰的味道
Bond!
彭德!
It's hot! What are you doing?
好燙...你到底在幹嘛?
A puppy? It's one of the resident's pet?
小狗?是住戶的寵物嗎?
You're quite impressive.
你真是能幹
Let's get out of here for now. Can you run?
總之先出去再說,跑得動嗎?
Stay low.
壓低身體
We can't go back...
不能走原路...
He's scared of the fire. I can't force him to go through.
牠在怕火,我不能逼牠穿過去
This is not good. What should I do?
這下不妙了,該怎麼辦?
The lower level is engulfed in flames.
樓下已經都是熊熊大火
Then that would leave us with the outside stairs on the north side.
那就只剩北側外部的樓梯
It'll be dangerous, but that'll be our only choice.
雖然危險,但那是唯一的生路了
Come, Bond!
走吧,彭德!
What is it? This is no time for playing.
怎麼了?現在沒時間玩了
Y... you saved us.
你...你救了我們
You can sniff out danger at times like this too?
這種時候你也可以嗅到危險嗎?
You're amazing.
真厲害
We can't use the outside stairs.
這樣也不能用外部樓梯了
That means we'll have to force our way through the smoke.
也就是說 我們必須強行突破濃煙前進
I can manage, but Bond won't be able to breathe.
我是沒問題,但彭德會無法呼吸
A plastic bag?
塑膠袋?
All right, let's use this
好,就用這個
to trap in clean air from the bottom like so.
把底部的新鮮空氣收集起來
It's a simple substitute for an oxygen tank.
這樣就是簡易的氧氣囊了
We'll use this in areas where we can't breathe.
要是到了無法呼吸的地方 就把這個拿出來用
Let's carry the puppy in here.
把小狗狗放到背包裡吧
Don't go astray! Follow me closely!
別迷路了,一定要好好跟緊我!
Let's go.
走了!
You made it out safely?
你平安無事啊?
This little one
407號的住戶
was left behind in room 407.
似乎把這孩子留在那裡了
Oh! This is Ms. Bennett's puppy!
這是貝涅特小姐養的狗啊!
She was still inside?
原來牠還在裡面嗎?
You guys ran in there to save her?
你們特地跑進去救牠?
Your dog is very impressive.
你家的狗狗真是厲害
Bond! You're on fire!
彭德,你著火了!
Hold on! I'll bring a bucket of water!
等等,我去提桶水來!
He's so thin!
好瘦喔!
This is what you look like when you're wet?
原來你淋溼之後看起來是這樣啊?
I've never seen him like this before,
因為洗澡都是約兒小姐負責
since Yor always gives him a bath. But this is...
這還是我第一次看到 牠這個樣子,實在是...
No, hold it in, Twilight.
不行,要忍住,黃昏
I'm a cool-headed spy. I must not let my emotions show.
我可是冷酷的間諜 不能隨便表露出內在的情感
The fire is out now. Good for you.
火已經撲滅了,真是太好了
What is it?
怎麼了?
Hey! Sir.
喂!大叔
- Please look after that puppy! - S... sure.
- 那隻小狗就拜託你了! - 哦...好
Hold up, Bond!
等等啊,彭德!
Whoa. Look at those flames!
讚啦,看看那個火勢!
Daisy!
黛西!
Ma'am, it's dangerous! Stand back!
太太,不可以,請後退!
Daisy is still inside!
黛西還在裡面!
This is so addictive!
真叫人上癮啊!
What's that wet, skinny thing?
這個溼答答又瘦巴巴的東西是什麼?
- Let go of me! Dammit! - Is he biting another stranger?!
- 放開我,可惡! - 那傢伙又跑去咬陌生人?
You little...
混帳東西...
Oil and lighters?
燃油跟打火機?
Don't underestimate humans, you little mutt!
少瞧不起人類了,臭畜牲!
You knew that this guy was the arsonist?
你早就知道這傢伙是縱火犯?
This is the type of oil
這種燃油
used by the serial arsonist that the authorities are after.
也剛好是當局緝查的 縱火犯所用的種類
Let's report him to the police and leave the rest up to them.
總之先報警吧 剩下的就交給警方去處理
Good work on catching him.
真虧你能逮到他
Did you pick up a scent at the scene? Or did you sniff out his stress sweat?
你在現場聞到他的味道嗎? 還是聞到犯人因為壓力冒汗的味道?
Either way, you did a great job.
無論如何,你都立了大功
I'm so glad! Daisy!
太好了,黛西!
I'm so glad you're safe!
妳平安無事真是太好了!
What a relief!
真的是太好了!
I wouldn't have been able to live without you...
萬一失去妳的話,我就...
My Daisy! I'm so sorry!
黛西,對不起
A serious looking guy,
是一個看起來很正經的小哥
and a huge, super thin dog rescued your puppy.
還有一隻瘦巴巴的大狗救了牠喔
They really deserve a medal.
他們真是值得表揚一番
Where did they go? Let me go look for them.
他們去哪了?我去找一下
Let's go.
走吧
It won't be good for either of us to be in the newspaper.
對你我而言,上報紙可不是什麼好事
Let's reward this doggie for his work with a year's worth of meat!
就用一年份的肉犒賞這隻狗狗吧!
You did well! You were amazing. But...
做得很好!很棒喔,不過...
You're supposed to bite the arm, not the leg!
應該要咬手而不是咬腿啊!
Don't be reckless.
不要這麼莽撞
There's people at home who will be sad if you die.
你要是死了,家裡有人會很傷心喔
I'm sorry too.
我也有不對的地方
Your role as a working dog should only come second.
擔任工作犬的角色只是其次
Understand that first and foremost, you are a member of the Forger family.
你要明白在那之前 你先是佛傑家的狗狗
Got it?
懂嗎?
Are you not hurt?
沒受傷吧?
You must have breathed in a lot of smoke.
剛剛一定吸了很多濃煙
Let's get you checked out at the vet just in case.
保險起見 還是帶你去給獸醫檢查一下
Hey, what is it? Stop it!
怎麼啦?好了,別鬧了!
Don't get carried away. I just want the Forger family
別得意忘形了,我只是希望佛傑家
to stay together for my best interests...
不會瓦解,純粹是出於個人利益...
I don't have any extra missions tomorrow
明天我沒有其他任務
so let's all go to the dog park together.
大家一起去狗狗公園吧
You've been all alone lately staying home by yourself.
最近都留你一個人看家 沒讓你享受到假期吧
Why does your bark change when you get wet?
怎麼淋溼之後連叫聲都變了?
I did it!
完成了!
- Is that a knife? - Oh?
- 是刀子嗎? - 咦?
It's a penguin.
是企鵝
Origami is pretty difficult, huh?
摺紙果然很難呢
Oh yeah, how about something like this?
對了,那這樣怎麼樣?
Ta-da!
鏘鏘!
Oh... I cut it a bit too much.
哎呀...稍微剪過頭了
I'm back.
我回來了
Welcome back.
歡迎回來
Bond! You're all wilted and shriveled!
彭德怎麼變得瘦瘦癟癟的?
Oh my, what happened?
這是怎麼回事?
Oh, there was a bit of an accident.
遇上了一點小意外
We got splashed with water on the way home.
回家的路上被水噴到
Oh, I see.
原來如此
His bark sounds different too!
牠的叫聲也跟平常不一樣!
Don't worry, Anya.
放心吧,安妮亞
This is what happens to Bond when he gets wet.
彭德先生淋溼的時候就會這樣
He'll be back to his fluffy self once his fur dries.
毛乾了之後 就會變回原來蓬蓬的樣子了
He rescued a puppy from a fire,
牠從大火中救出一隻小狗
and caught an arsonist.
還抓到縱火犯
But I can't tell them what really happened.
但我卻不能把實情告訴她們
Father and Bond achieved great things during their walk!
父親跟彭德散步時做了了不起的事
Give me a second, Bond.
彭德先生,請等一下
- I'll get you dried right away. - Thanks, Yor.
- 我馬上幫你弄乾 - 麻煩妳了,約兒小姐
Father.
父親
Father, and Bond! I award you both with a Stella Star!
父親跟彭德,給你們各頒一枚星星!
You're playing pretend with Stella Stars?
什麼啊?是在玩頒星星的遊戲?
It's the "You Worked Super Hard While Taking A Walk" award.
這是“散步時也非常努力”獎
Wow! Loid, and Bond, congratulations!
彭德先生、洛伊德先生,恭喜你們!
This is all great, but please earn yourself a real Stella Star.
怎樣都好啦 還不如拿個真的星星回來
Oh god...
什麼...
All right, time to prepare dinner.
好,該準備做晚飯了
I'll help.
我來幫忙
I want to eat Father's Hamburg steak!
安妮亞想吃父親做的漢堡排!
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻譯:洪貞韻